# **CHRISTOPHER HART**

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

☑chris.ryan.hart1@gmail.com \$8595360656

ttps://chrisryanhart.github.io/portfolio/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/chrisryanhart ttps://github.com/chrisryanhart

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Software Engineer with JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Node.js, Python, and PostgreSQL skills. Prior experience as a Mechanical Engineer leading diverse cross-functional teams in pharmaceutical and auto manufacturing using tools like Six Sigma to tackle production issues. Hones software skills by integrating past problem-solving experience to systematically design, test, and optimize web applications.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, SQL, CSS, HTML

Software Development: React.js, AJAX, PostgreSQL, Node.js, Express.js, Flask, API Design, Jest, Git, Agile

Engineering: Data Structures & Algorithms, Engineer in Training (EIT), Six Sigma, Root Cause Analysis, 8D Problem Solving

#### **PROJECTS**

Aug. 2023-Present Caregiver App

 Chingu team project that reduces the burden of guardians caring for terminally ill family by facilitating communication of needs so that friends know how to help

**Tech Stack**: React.js, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB

Climbing Meetup App - https://climbing-meetup.surge.sh/

Dec 2022-Jan. 2023

- Facilitate meetups between climbing partners by enabling users to create a profile, create meetups, and view all meetups they are attending
- Tech Stack: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Jest, and Material-UI (MUI)

College Value App - <a href="https://college-value-app.herokuapp.com/">https://college-value-app.herokuapp.com/</a>

Aug. 2022-Sept. 2023

- Empower prospective college students to easily identify school cost and income post-graduation by saving their custom searches to their own profile
- Tech Stack: Python, Flask, JavaScript, SQLAlchemy, Jinja, jQuery, WTForms, CSS, and HTML

# RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

#### **Chingu Team Project, Certification**

Aug. 2023-Present

Software Developer Fellow

Cultivating Agile, Git, and teamwork skills by creating a web application with a volunteer, project-based, learning platform. Mastering development in a simulated, professional environment by participating in weekly sprints to set goals, address roadblocks, and perform stand-ups.

# Springboard Software Engineering Boot Camp, Certification Software Engineering Fellow

May 2022-Feb. 2023

 Completed 700+ hours of hands-on course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 portfolio in-depth projects covering frontend web development, backend web development, and full stack development. Mastered skills in JavaScript, DOM Manipulation, Git, AJAX, ¡Query, Python, Flask, SQL, PostgreSQL, Node.js, Express, React.js, and Jest

# **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Catalent Pharma Solutions, Winchester, KY

March 2021-May 2022

#### **Process Engineer**

- Continuously improved production efficiency and cut costs by reducing process turnaround, setup, and cleaning times
- Quantified top maintenance issues through a Python script creating comprehensive shift summary report
- Led integration of automated Clean-in-Place equipment into production processes to reduce cost of a lengthy cleaning process

# Hitachi Astemo (formerly Hitachi Automotive Systems), Harrodsburg, KY

July 2013-April 2020

Industrial Engineer

Sept. 2019-April 2020

- Increased production output and cut costs by identifying bottlenecks and developing countermeasures
- Influenced team members to adopt a simple standard procedure modification resulting in a \$5,000 savings and a 10% throughput increase
- Employed Value Stream Mapping concepts to identify a root cause and develop a countermeasure for a 20% reduction in cycle time and an additional 240 pcs/shift

# **Quality Assurance Assistant Manager**

Feb. 2017-Aug. 2019

- Led a small team to enhance product quality and cut costs by eliminating production issues
- Identified a process issue and a countermeasure through a Root Cause Analysis for a part causing a supply-chain shortage, increasing line output by 5% from scrap reduction.
- Resolved customer concerns about a major process change by communicating risks, resulting in a simplified and feasible trial build requirement.

# **Quality Assurance Engineer**

July 2013-Jan. 2017

- Improved Electronic Throttle Body product quality and cut costs by preventing and eliminating issues
- Eliminated a high safety severity issue for the customer through Root Cause Analysis that helped avoid a government recall
- Reduced a major welding defect by 79.2% by creating a data retrieval system and an unconventional vision monitoring system to analyze defects

# Cummins Inc., Columbus, IN

Feb. 2011-Nov. 2012

Product Development Engineer

Validated the diesel fuel system by conducting tests and leading failure investigations with Root Cause Analysis

### **EDUCATION**

#### **SPRINGBOARD**

Software Engineering Career Track

May 2022-Feb. 2023

# **UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY, Lexington, KY**

Aug. 2015-Dec. 2017

Masters of Business Administration

- Obtained Six Sigma (6S) DMAIC Green Belt Certification
- Entrepreneurship Bootcamp Graduate

#### **UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY, Lexington, KY**

Aug. 2005-Dec. 2010

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering